Guide to the Robert Byron Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Robert Byron Papers
1866-2005
1909-1914
GEN MSS 605
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
34.65
(68 boxes) + 10 broadside folders
The Robert Byron Papers consist of correspondence, writings, photographs, drawings, and other material that document his work as a writer and art critic. The Papers provide evidence of Byron's travels and writing career as well as his work as a propagandist during World War II.
Byron, Robert, 1905-1941
Waughburton, Richard
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Bernard Quaritch on the James Marshall and Marie-Louise Osborn Collection Fund and the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2006-2008.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Restricted Fragile Material is in cold storage and may be consulted only with permission of the appropriate curator. Photographic prints for reference use have been substituted in the main files.
Robert Byron (1905-1941)
Robert Byron, writer and art critic, was born in London and educated at Eton College and Merton College, Oxford University. Byron was the first of three children born to Eric Byron, a civil engineer, and Margaret Robinson Byron, an amateur artist. Byron made a career out of writing about his extensive travels and his first book, Europe in the Looking-Glass (1926), is based on his travels to Germany, Italy, and Greece while still an undergraduate student. Byron's later travels to Greece (1926, 1927, and 1931), and fascination with Byzantine art, were also inspiration for his books The Station (1928), The Byzantine Achievement (1929), and The Birth of Western Painting (1931).
In 1929 Byron flew to India for the Daily Express in order to write a series of articles on the Indian air mail. Once in India, Byron continued his travels throughout the region (including a stint in Tibet) which he wrote about in articles as well as in his book An Essay on India (1931). Byron later recounted his travels in Tibet following a trip to Russia (1932) in his book First Russia, Then Tibet (1933).
In 1933 and 1934 Byron traveled to the Middle East, spending time largely in Persia and Afghanistan, but also passing through Cyprus, Palestine, Syria, and Iraq. These travels resulted in Byron's best known book: The Road to Oxiana (1937). Byron collaborated with Christopher Sykes to publish the novel Innocence and Design (1935) under the pseudonym "Richard Waughburton" in which they drew on their experiences in Persia (now Iran). Byron also wrote an essay, "Timurid Architecture", for Arthur Upham Pope's Survey of Persian Art (1938) based on his observations of Persian architecture. On his return to England Byron worked on two travel books on the British Isles: Shell Guide to Wiltshire (1935) and Imperial Pilgrimage (1937). Byron continued traveling after his trip to the Middle East, including trips to America, Russia, Siberia, China, and Japan, reporting on his experiences in newspapers and journals.
Byron wrote on art and architecture in both his travel narratives and in other projects (such as The Appreciation of Architecture published in 1927). He was also a founding member of the Georgian Group, which was established in 1937 as an offshoot of the Society for the Protection of Ancient Buildings.
In the late thirties and early forties Byron's chief preoccupation was with Nazism and World War II. While Byron's pursuit of a position with the military was unsuccessful, he found outlets for political action in the Federal Union League and with the Ministry of Information. In 1938 Byron secured contract work with the Ministry of Information as a propagandist, for which he traveled to Germany and attended the Parteitag (the Nazi Party Congress). On his return to Britain the project ended and Byron ultimately joined the European News Department of the BBC. In 1940 Byron again became involved with government wartime endeavors and, under the guise of a Times correspondent, he was sent to Iran in order to observe Russian activity regarding Middle East oil. Byron died on his way to the Middle East on February 24, 1941 when the ship he was on was torpedoed.
Scope and Contents
The Robert Byron Papers document his work as a writer and art critic and span the dates 1866 to 2005 (predominantly dating between 1909 and 1941). The Papers contain correspondence, writings, personal papers, photographs, and drawings documenting Byron's personal and professional life. The Papers document Byron's engagement with travel, art history, history, and politics.
Papers such as research materials, drafts, publicity, and reviews provide evidence of Byron's writing career and creative process. Byron's travels, on which he wrote extensively, are documented in the Papers, and include observations on Greece, Afghanistan, Persia, India, Russia, Tibet, and China. Byron's journals and correspondence (particularly with his mother) record his initial observations while traveling and were a source for his publications. As an amateur photographer and artist Byron also created photographs and drawings while abroad, many of which he later used as illustrations in his publications.
In addition to documenting his travels, Byron's correspondence also provides evidence of his literary circle as well as relationships with editors and publishers. Among his correspondents are Evelyn Waugh, Harold Acton, John Betjeman, Arthur Upham Pope, and Edith Sitwell, and to a lesser extent, Somerset Maugham, George Bernard Shaw, Rebecca West, and Leonard Woolf. The Papers also record Byron's social circle, many of whom he became acquainted with while at Eton and Oxford, including Michael and Desmond Parsons, Bryan Guinness, and Christopher Sykes.
Byron's interest in politics (and particularly with Nazism and World War II) are documented in his reports on propaganda as well as papers relating to his involvement with the Federal Union League and as a journalist with the European News Department of the BBC.
In addition to his writings, Byron's other papers also provide evidence of his dedication to art and architecture, such as his involvement with the Georgian Group (which includes meeting minutes and drafts of related articles and lectures).
Arrangement
The Robert Byron Papers are organized into five series: Correspondence; Writings; Other Papers; Drawings and Photographs; and Family Papers.
Authors, British -- 20th Century -- Archives; British literature -- 20th Century; Travel writers -- Great Britain; Travel writing -- Technique; Travel writing; Travelers' writings, British -- 20th Century; Travelers' writings, English -- 20th Century; World War, 1939-1945 -- Journalists; World War, 1939-1945 -- Propaganda; Afghanistan -- Description and travel; Europe -- Description and travel; Iran -- Description and travel; Iraq -- Description and travel; Middle East -- Description and travel; Russia -- Description and travel; Tibet Autonomous Region (China) -- Description and travel; Diaries; Drawings (visual works); Photographs; Acton, Harold, 1904-1994; Antrim, Randal John Somerled McDonnell, Earl of, 1911-1977; Betjeman, John, 1906-1984; Byron, Robert, 1905-1941; Chetwode, Penelope; Guinness, Bryan, 1905-1992; Harrod, Roy, 1900-1978; Huxley, Michael; Kinross, Patrick Balfour, Baron, 1904-1976; Kyrou, Achil. A. (Achilleus A.); Lees-Milne, James, 1908-1997; Locker Lampson, Oliver, 1880-1954; Lutyens, Edwin Landseer, Sir, 1869-1944; Maugham, W. Somerset (William Somerset), 1874-1965; Messel, Oliver, 1904-1978; Mosley, Cynthia, Lady, 1898-1933; Parsons, Desmond, 1910-1937; Sackville-West, Edward, 1901-1965; Sitwell, Edith, 1887-1964; Stokes, Adrian, 1902-1972; Stuart Wortley, Violet, 1866-1953; Sykes, Christopher, 1907-1986; Waugh, Evelyn, 1903-1966; Waughburton, Richard; West, Rebecca, 1892-1983; Wicklow, William Cecil Forward Howard Clonmore, Earl of, 1902-1978; Wyndham, Violet; Young, G. M. (George Malcolm), 1882-1959; A.D. Peters (Firm); British Broadcasting Corporation; George Routledge and Sons; Georgian Group (London, England); Macmillan & Co
- Correspondence, 1900-1991; Series I; 6.46; (16 boxes)
  Arrangement
  The series is organized into two subseries: Family Correspondence and General Correspondence.
  Scope and Contents
  The series contains Byron's personal and professional correspondence dating from 1920 to 1941 and correspondence from third parties to Byron's parents and sister dating from 1900 to 1991. The series documents Byron's personal relationships and writing career. Family Correspondence contains correspondence exchanged between Byron and his immediate family (namely his parents and sisters), Byron's correspondence with extended family members, and third-party correspondence sent to Byron's parents and sisters (such as letters to Eric Byron and Lucy Butler addressing the legacy of Byron's papers). Byron's correspondence with his mother is particularly helpful in understanding his writing process because he drew from these letters in his publications (such as The Road to Oxiana ).
  Byron's friendships and relationships with editors and publishers are documented in General correspondence. Additional correspondence can be found in Writings (Series II) and Other Papers (Series III).
  - Family Correspondence
    The subseries is arranged under two headings: Correspondence Between Robert Byron and Immediate Family and Other Family Correspondence.
    - Correspondence Between Robert Byron and Immediate Family
      Arranged chronologically.
      - Outgoing
        - Eton College, 1920-1922 (Box 1, Folder 1-4)
        - Oxford University and Europe, 1923-1924 (Box 1, Folder 5-8)
        - Oxford University and Europe, 1925-1926 (Box 2, Folder 9-12)
        - England and Greece, 1927-1929 (Box 2, Folder 13-18)
        - Tibet, India, England, 1929-1931 (Box 3, Folder 19-22)
        - Russia, Persia, Afghanistan, 1932-1934 (Box 3, Folder 23-26)
          Includes photocopies
        - England, United States, Russia, China, Japan, 1935-1936 (Box 3, Folder 27-31)
        - England and Germany, 1937-1941 (Box 4, Folder 32-34)
        - Unidentified, undated (Box 4, Folder 35)
      - Incoming
        - 1928-1929 (Box 63, Folder 835-836)
        - 1930-1937 (Box 63, Folder 837)
        - 1938-1940 (Box 63, Folder 838-840)
        - Undated (Box 63, Folder 841)
    - Other Family Correspondence
      Arranged alphabetically.
      - General A-Z, 1900-1945 (Box 4, Folder 36-37)
      - Butler, Harold, 1934, undated (Box 4, Folder 38)
      - Butler, Lucy Byron, 1934-1991 (Box 4, Folder 39-42)
        Includes seven photographs taken by Robert Byron of buildings in New Delhi; photograph of Byron, Anne, and Lucy
        Includes additional third party correspondence regarding Byron's papers
      - Butler, Lucy Byron, circa 1976; Outgoing carbon of letter to David Pryce-Jones (Box 62, Folder 825)
      - Butler, Lucy Byron, 1980-1987 (Box 63, Folder 842-845)
        Includes copies of The Spectator
      - Byron, Anne, 1939-1944, undated (Box 4, Folder 43)
      - Byron, Arthur, 1941-1946, undated (Box 5, Folder 44)
      - Byron, Cecil, 1900-1941 (Box 5, Folder 45)
      - Byron, Edmund, 1919, undated (Box 5, Folder 46)
      - Byron, Eric M., 1921-1943 (Box 5, Folder 47)
      - Byron, Eric M., 1945-1964 (Box 63, Folder 846)
        Includes correspondence with A.D. Peters regarding Robert Byron's literary legacy
      - Byron, Hugh, 1935-1946, undated (Box 5, Folder 48)
      - Byron, John, 1929-1944, undated (Box 5, Folder 49)
      - Byron, Margaret Robinson, 1939-1946, undated (Box 5, Folder 50)
      - Byron, Margaret Robinson, 1935-1946 (Box 63, Folder 847-849)
      - Byron, Thomas, 1928-1940 (Box 5, Folder 51-52)
      - Charlesworth, Mark P., 1936-1940 (Box 5, Folder 53)
      - Chater, Gertrude, undated (Box 63, Folder 850)
      - Ellis, Edith and F.H., 1928-1946 (Box 5, Folder 54)
      - E.P. Rugg and Company, 1938-1939 (Box 5, Folder 55)
      - Eton College, 1908-1920 (Box 5, Folder 56)
      - Hall Hall, Lucy, 1917-1944, undated (Box 5, Folder 57-59)
      - Hilton, Eva and Charles, 1929-1936, undated (Box 5, Folder 60)
      - Jeffreys, Harry, 1922-1946, undated (Box 6, Folder 61)
      - Keehn, Anne, 1928, undated (Box 6, Folder 62)
      - Oxford University, 1922 (Box 6, Folder 63)
      - Reynolds, J., 1931-1947 (Box 6, Folder 64)
      - Robinson, Alice Chater, 1929-1943, undated (Box 6, Folder 65)
      - Robinson, Edith, 1938, undated (Box 63, Folder 851)
      - Robinson, Gertrude, undated (Box 6, Folder 65a)
      - Robinson, Gladys, 1934, undated (Box 6, Folder 66)
      - Robinson, Rose and Norman, 1928-1935, undated (Box 6, Folder 67)
      - Russell and Company Solicitors, 1943-1944 (Box 6, Folder 68)
      - Tedworth Hunt, 1923-1935 (Box 6, Folder 69)
      - Trower, Edith, 1935-1935, undated (Box 6, Folder 70)
      - Urban District of Coulsdon, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 71)
      - W., E.E., 1938-1940, undated (Box 6, Folder 72)
      - First name only, 1924-1952, undated (Box 6, Folder 73-74)
      - Envelopes, 1926- (Box 6, Folder 75-76)
  - General Correspondence
    - "A" General, 1931-1940, undated (Box 6, Folder 77)
    - Abdy, Bertie, 1932-1941, undated (Box 6, Folder 78)
    - Acton, Harold Mario Mitchell, 1928-1940, undated (Box 6, Folder 79)
    - Acton, William, 1939, undated (Box 6, Folder 80)
    - Allen, William, 1931-1935, undated (Box 6, Folder 81)
    - The American Mercury, 1935-1937 (Box 6, Folder 82)
    - Anderson, Colin, 1935-1937 (Box 6, Folder 83)
    - The Anglo-Hellenic League, 1935-1939 (Box 6, Folder 84)
    - Antrim, Randal John Somerled McDonnell, 8th Earl of, 1935-1940, undated (Box 6, Folder 85-86)
    - The Architectural Association, 1933-1940 (Box 7, Folder 87)
    - The Architectural Press, 1928-1938 (Box 7, Folder 88)
      Related Archival Materials note
      See also: Barman, Christian
    - Aritaki, Shoji, 1936-1937, undated (Box 7, Folder 89)
    - Arnold, Elizabeth, 1934-1938 (Box 7, Folder 90)
    - Atchley, Shirley Clifford, 1925-1926 (Box 7, Folder 91)
    - "B" General, 1931-1946 (Box 7, Folder 92-93)
    - Baird, ----., undated (Box 7, Folder 94)
    - Balfour, John, undated (Box 7, Folder 95)
    - Barclay's Bank Limited, 1934-1941 (Box 7, Folder 96)
    - Barman, Christian, 1933-1937 (Box 7, Folder 97)
      See also: The Architectural Press
    - Bath, Henry, 1934-1938 (Box 7, Folder 98)
    - Beaton, Cecil, 1940, undated (Box 7, Folder 99)
    - Beauchamp, William Lygon, 7th Earl of, 1923-1937, undated (Box 7, Folder 100)
    - Beauchamp, William Lygon, 8th Earl of, 1938-1940 (Box 7, Folder 101)
    - Beddington, Jack, 1931-1939 (Box 7, Folder 102)
    - Beefsteak Club, 1937-1941 (Box 7, Folder 103)
    - Bentick, Ruth, 1938-1939, undated (Box 7, Folder 104)
    - Bernays, Robert, 1931-1939, undated (Box 7, Folder 105)
    - Betjeman, John, 1932-1937 (Box 7, Folder 106)
    - Bousios, Basil Nicholas Hellenagoras, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 107)
    - Bowra, C.M. (Cecil Maurice), 1927, undated (Box 7, Folder 108)
    - Brian Gore-Booth and Company, 1938-1941 (Box 7, Folder 109)
    - Britain in Pictures (Penns in the Rocks Press), 1940-1941 (Box 7, Folder 110)
    - British and International Press Limited, 1937-1938 (Box 7, Folder 111)
    - British Broadcasting Corporation, 1932-1941 (Box 7, Folder 112)
    - The British Council, 1937-1940 (Box 7, Folder 113)
    - Bullard, Reader, Sir, 1933, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 114)
    - The Burlington Magazine Limited, 1932-1937 (Box 7, Folder 115)
    - Butler, R., 1937-1939 (Box 7, Folder 116)
    - Butler, Ewan, 1937-1940, undated (Box 7, Folder 117)
    - "C" General, 1929-1940 (Box 8, Folder 118-119)
    - Carrington, Neil, 1938, undated (Box 8, Folder 120)
    - Casson, Hugh Maxwell, Sir, 1937, undated (Box 8, Folder 121)
    - Chappell and Company Limited, 1935-1939 (Box 8, Folder 122)
    - Chater, Wolfe, 1938, undated (Box 8, Folder 123)
    - Chetwode, Penelope, 1933-1938, undated (Box 8, Folder 124)
    - Clarke, Dorothy, 1937-1941 (Box 8, Folder 125-128)
    - Clark, Kenneth, 1934-1938, undated (Box 8, Folder 129)
    - Clodius, Carl, undated (Box 8, Folder 130)
      Includes photograph of group of unidentified people picnicking
    - Clonmore, William Cecil Forward Howard, Lord, 1921-1946, undated (Box 8, Folder 131-132)
    - Colefax, Sibyl, 1934-1940, undated (Box 8, Folder 133)
    - Corbett and Newson Limited, 1937-1938 (Box 8, Folder 134)
    - Country Life, 1928-1939 (Box 8, Folder 135)
      See also: Hussey, Christopher
    - Courtauld Institute of Art, 1936-1948, undated (Box 8, Folder 136)
    - "D" General, 1931-1941, undated (Box 8, Folder 137)
    - Daily Express, 1931-1939, undated (Box 8, Folder 138)
    - Dalton, Hugh, Ruth, and O.M., 1928-1937 (Box 8, Folder 139)
    - Dashwood, Helen, 1938 (Box 8, Folder 140)
    - Del Drago, G., 1932 (Box 8, Folder 141)
      Includes two photographs of painting "The Paradise"
    - Dinley, Mark, 1931-1939, undated (Box 8, Folder 142)
    - Douglas, Norman, 1934-1937 (Box 8, Folder 143)
    - Drury, F.S.E., 1937-1938 (Box 8, Folder 144)
    - Duggan, Alfred Leo, 1928, undated (Box 8, Folder 145)
      Includes postcard sent jointly with Tom, Desmond [Parsons?], John [Heygate?]
    - "E" General, 1928-1941, undated (Box 9, Folder 146)
    - Eastern Command and London Welfare Branch, 1940, undated (Box 9, Folder 147)
    - Eden, Anthony, Earl of Avon, 1935-1938 (Box 9, Folder 148)
    - Emanuel, Bill, 1937-1938 (Box 9, Folder 149)
    - "F" General, 1931-1940, undated (Box 9, Folder 150)
    - Fay, Ronald, 1940-1941, undated (Box 9, Folder 151)
    - Fletcher, Ted, 1936-1938, undated (Box 9, Folder 152)
    - Ford, Richard, 1939-1940 (Box 9, Folder 153)
    - Forster, E.M. (Edward Morgan), 1931 June 6 (Box 9, Folder 154)
    - Francis Edwards Limited, 1935-1940 (Box 9, Folder 155)
    - French, G.C., 1934, undated (Box 9, Folder 156)
    - Fullerton, ----., 1935-1937, undated (Box 9, Folder 157)
    - "G" General, 1929-1941, undated (Box 9, Folder 158)
    - Garrick Club, 1938-1941 (Box 9, Folder 159)
    - The Geographical Magazine, 1940-1941 (Box 9, Folder 160)
      See also: Huxley, Michael
    - George Routledge and Sons Limited, 1927-1935 (Box 9, Folder 161)
      Includes contract for The Birth of Western Painting
    - Georgian Group, 1932-1940 (Box 9, Folder 162-164)
    - Glenconner, Pamela, 1935 (Box 9, Folder 165)
    - Gloag, John, 1933-1939 (Box 9, Folder 166)
    - Goldman, Bosworth, 1932-1940, undated (Box 9, Folder 167)
    - Government of the N.W. Frontier Province (India), 1933 (Box 9, Folder 168)
    - Gowing, Lawrence, 1939, undated (Box 9, Folder 169)
    - Great Britain. War Office, 1934-1941 (Box 9, Folder 170)
    - Great Western Royal Hotel, 1940-1941 (Box 9, Folder 171)
    - Green, Henry, 1928-1941, undated (Box 9, Folder 172)
    - Group Theatre, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 173)
    - Guinness, Bryan, 1927-1939 (Box 9, Folder 174)
    - "H" General, 1928-1941, undated (Box 10, Folder 175-176)
    - Hall, E.E., 1931 (Box 10, Folder 177)
    - Hammersby, V., 1937-1938, undated (Box 10, Folder 178)
    - Harper's Bazaar, 1933-1936 (Box 10, Folder 179)
    - Harris, Audrey, 1937, undated (Box 10, Folder 180)
    - Harrison, R.K., 1939 (Box 10, Folder 181)
    - Harrod, Frances, undated (Box 10, Folder 182)
    - Harrod, Roy Forbes, Sir, 1932-1941 (Box 10, Folder 183)
    - Henderson, Gavin, 1926-1940 (Box 10, Folder 184)
    - Hensman, Stuart, 1937-1940 (Box 10, Folder 185)
    - Hill, Derek, 1934-1935, undated (Box 10, Folder 186)
    - Hofmarschall, Dienstt, 1934-1939 (Box 10, Folder 187)
    - Hogland, Winnie, 1934-1937, undated (Box 10, Folder 188)
      Includes six black and white photographs of Zanté (Greece)
    - Hulton Press Limited, 1940 (Box 10, Folder 189)
    - Hussey, Betty, 1937-1939, undated (Box 10, Folder 190)
    - Hussey, Christopher, 1932-1940, undated (Box 10, Folder 191)
      See also: Country Life
    - Huxley, Michael, 1934-1935 (Box 10, Folder 192)
      See also: The Geographical Magazine
    - "I" General, 1932-1939, undated (Box 10, Folder 193)
    - "J" General, 1934-1940, undated (Box 10, Folder 194)
    - J. Simmonds and Company, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 195)
    - John Poole and Sons Limited, 1940-1941 (Box 10, Folder 196)
    - "K" General, 1928-1939, undated (Box 10, Folder 197)
    - Kahn, Addie, 1938-1939, undated (Box 10, Folder 198)
    - Kauffer, McKnight, 1932-1939, undated (Box 10, Folder 199)
    - Kimber, Charles, 1937-1939, undated (Box 10, Folder 200)
    - King, Raymond, 1936-1937 (Box 10, Folder 201)
    - King, Sohstu G., 1936-1938, undated (Box 10, Folder 202)
    - King, William Augustus Henry, 1928-1939, undated (Box 10, Folder 203)
    - Kinross, Patrick Balfour, Baron, 1934, undated (Box 10, Folder 204)
    - Kodak Limited, 1934-1935 (Box 10, Folder 205)
    - Kyrou, Achil. A. (Achilleus A.), 1931-1932, undated (Box 10, Folder 206)
    - "L" General, 1928-1941, undated (Box 11, Folder 207)
    - Lacy, Alec, 1939 (Box 11, Folder 208)
    - Lamb, Henry, 1932-1937, undated (Box 11, Folder 209)
    - Langham Hotel Company Limited, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 210)
    - Lansdowne, Elsie, 1938 (Box 11, Folder 211)
    - Layton, George A., 1936-1937, undated (Box 11, Folder 212)
    - Leconfield, Violet, 1932-1938, undated (Box 11, Folder 213)
    - Lees-Milne, James, 1937-1940, undated (Box 11, Folder 214)
    - Lid Van De International Air Traffic Association, 1928-1938 (Box 11, Folder 215)
    - The Listener (British Broadcasting Corporation), 1934-1938 (Box 11, Folder 216)
    - Locker Lampson, Oliver, 1930-1941 (Box 11, Folder 217)
    - Lockhart, Lawrence, 1939-1940 (Box 11, Folder 218)
    - London Film Productions Limited, 1934-1937 (Box 11, Folder 219)
    - London Library, 1932-1939 (Box 11, Folder 220)
    - The London Mercury, 1932-1937, undated (Box 11, Folder 221)
    - Loraime, Louise, 1939, undated (Box 11, Folder 222)
    - Lutyens, Edwin Landseer, Sir, 1931-1941 (Box 11, Folder 223)
    - Lygon, Dorothy; Lygon, Hugh; Lygon, Mary, 1933-1937, undated (Box 11, Folder 224)
      Includes photograph of Mary Lygon
    - "M" General, 1929-1940, undated (Box 11, Folder 225-226)
    - McDonald, Malcolm, 1936 (Box 11, Folder 227)
    - MacMillan and Company Limited, 1933-1950 (Box 11, Folder 228-229)
    - Maconochie, Richard, 1935-1937, undated (Box 11, Folder 230)
    - Mallet, Peggy, 1936-1939, undated (Box 11, Folder 231)
    - Mallet, Victor, 1934-1938, undated (Box 11, Folder 232)
    - Marsh, Eddie, 1931-1937, undated (Box 11, Folder 233)
    - Matthews, Reverend C.H.S., undated (Box 11, Folder 234)
    - Matthews, ----., 1934-1936, undated (Box 11, Folder 235)
    - Maugham, W. Somerset (William Somerset), undated (Box 11, Folder 236)
    - Mavrogordato, John, 1932-1938 (Box 11, Folder 237)
    - Messel, Oliver, 1938 (Box 11, Folder 238)
    - Miller, W., 1928, undated (Box 11, Folder 239)
    - Millet, Gabriel, 1929-1935, undated (Box 11, Folder 240)
    - Ministry of Labour, 1939 (Box 11, Folder 241)
    - Moray, Barbara, 1939-1941, undated (Box 11, Folder 242)
    - Morrell, Ottoliné Violet Anne Cavendish-Bentinck, Lady, 1936, undated (Box 11, Folder 243)
    - Mosley, Cynthia, Lady, undated (Box 11, Folder 244)
    - Murray, Jock, 1934 (Box 11, Folder 245)
    - "N" General, 1923-1940, undated (Box 12, Folder 246)
    - Nash, Paul, 1932-1939, undated (Box 12, Folder 247)
    - The New Statesmen and Nation, 1932-1941, undated (Box 12, Folder 248)
    - The New York Times, 1935, undated (Box 12, Folder 249)
    - Nicolson, Harold George, Sir, 1931-1940 (Box 12, Folder 250)
    - "O" General, 1931-1940, undated (Box 12, Folder 251)
    - O'Connor, Scott, 1932, undated (Box 12, Folder 252)
    - Odhams Press Limited, 1937-1940 (Box 12, Folder 253)
    - Ogawa, H.T., 1936-1938 (Box 12, Folder 254)
    - Oldham, C.E.A.W., 1933 (Box 12, Folder 255)
    - Oliver, Alan E., 1938 (Box 12, Folder 256)